Hurry up!
빨리 움직이십시오
The gate won't close!
닫을 수 없어
Hey, is the gate closed yet?
어이, 다 됐어?
Hurry up!
빨리
Damn it...
젠장
What is that?
저건 뭐야…
What is going on now? I want a status report!
어떻게 된 건지 정보 좀 줘요
Hurry up!
빨리 빨리
-The Extinction Belt has descended so low. -Show me the footage of camera 2!
-단절의 띠가 이렇게까지 내려오다니 -얼른 2번 모니터 영상 전송해
Anomaly detected.
괴이 이상 발생
There is no sign of it receding.
처리하기 힘들 것 같다
Yuito...
유이토…
What is your ETA?
언제쯤 도착해?
We'll arrive in 30 minutes.
30분 뒤에
I see...
그래…
How is the situation?
지금 어때?
It's pretty bad.
엉망이야
It's still shaking
여전히 흔들리고 있어서
and causing all sorts of malfunctions to the defense system.
방어 시스템이 계속 고장난 상태야
On top of that, the Extinction Belt is still descending.
그리고 단절의 띠도 점점 더 밑으로 내려오고 있어
The activity of Kunad Gate along with gravitational anomaly...
쿠나도 게이트가 활약적이라 중력도 이상이 생긴건가…
If the Extinction Belt continues to descend...
단절의 띠가 계속해서 내려오면
It's going to happen again...
또…
How is Yuito holding up?
유이토 상태는 어때?
He's still unconscious.
아직 깨어나지 못했어
Sometimes he seems to be in great pain.
가끔은 또 고통스러워 보여…
We'll ready the ward for him.
병실을 알아보긴 하겠지만
But given the circumstances,
지금… 이런 상황에서
I wonder if there is any hospital that is available.
받아줄 병원이 있을지 모르겠어
Thanks.
고마워
SCARLET NEXUS
"스칼렛넥서"
♫Felling of tiredness is losing yourself♫
나른해 losing yourself
♫How do you still create a relationship each other♫
관계를 이룰 방법을 못 찾은 건가
♫It’s my awkward friend’s fault♫
귀찮은 친구가 있어
♫Until death, wanting someone somewhere to embrace me♫
죽을 때까지 누군가의 포옹을 원해
♫While the devil is not here and between the chaos♫
겨우 숨 돌리는 혼돈과 허무함 속에
♫Aiming between win and lose♫
승리와 실패 사이에 목표를 둬
♫Not to be running out of patience for now, I’m trying to be careful♫
믿음을 벼랑 끝으로 몰지 마 조심해
♫You’ll see I’m always on your side♫
You'll see I'm always on your side
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫You’re frigid and your roller coaster inside the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 궤도에 말이야
♫The grungy days and the unprecedented catastrophy♫
흔들었던 날들에는 없는 재난
♫Where is the glory buried?♫
영광은 어딘가에 묻어둔 지 오래
♫The lonely monster in a moment♫
이 순간 외로운 야수가
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫To pierce with the theory♫
세상의 모든 이치를 꿰뚫어
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 죽을힘을 다해 연락해
♫The bullet shot by the machinegun goes parallelly♫
날아드는 탄알과 함께
♫I tried hard to connect today as well♫
오늘도 여전히 함께해 똑똑히 연락해
♫You’re frigid and the theory in the brain♫
네 머릿속 차가운 정의에 말이야
INTO THE CRYPT
(스메라기 릉을 향해)
Yuito, hang in there.
유이토, 조금만 더 참아
Hanabi, I know you are worried,
하나비, 많이 걱정되겠지만
but it's too risky to teleport with Yuito.
지금 유이토와 함께 순간 이동하는 건 많이 위험해
Yes...
응…
Luka, sorry.
루카, 미안해
It's all right.
아니야
Will he be OK?
괜찮은걸까?
Maybe he's never going to wake up again.
이대로 못 깨어나는건 아니겠지…
That can't be...
그럴리가 없잖아…
That's not possible.
그건 아니야
He threw a lot of arrogant words at me just now.
나한테 쓸데없는 소리를 많이 하더군
Before he can prove his ideal is right,
자신의 생각이 맞다는 걸 증명하기 전에는
he's not going to die just yet.
그렇게 쉽게 죽지 못할거야
Chief, I can say about you too.
본부장님도 마찬가지겠네요
Due to the emergency,
긴급 사태 때문에
your authority as Chief has been restored.
본부장 권리를 잠시 회복하세요
Upon arriving Suoh,
스오에 도착하면
please continue to command the OSF.
계속하여 토벌군을 지휘하시죠
That's all.
이게 맞겠죠?
Even an expandable pawn
버려진 말이지만
must be utilized to the very end.
필요한 곳에 쓰겠다는 건가
It's the correct political decision.
정치적 판단은 아주 정확해
Error on the defense system!
방어 시스템 에러입니다
No confirmed downtime yet.
언제 복구될지 확인 불가능합니다
Arahabaki is the foundation for all, start repairing it now!
아라하바키가 없으면 안돼 당장 복구해
Gates of certain shelters can't be closed.
일부 피난처의 문을 닫지 못하고 있습니다
OSF soldiers are doing their best to stop the Others' advance.
토벌군은 현재 괴이와 맞서 싸우고 있지만
But it's only a matter of time before they break through our defense.
방어가 뚤리는 건 시간 문제입니다
We are fighting an uphill battle.
인원이 많이 부족합니다
Our formation has been scattered, we can't coordinate in battle!
진형이 전부 망가져 작전이 어렵습니다
Abandon the inoperational defense system.
기능을 잃은 방어 시스템은 버려
Chief Sumeragi!
스메라기 본부장님
Order all the soldiers deployed near the inoperable AA guns
작동을 멈춘 고사포 부근의 병사들은
to evacuate to shelters.
모두 피난처를 보호하도록 명령해
All stranded troops must return to headquarters at once.
지원 받지 못한 부대들은 지금 당장 본부로 철수하고
We'll regroup.
진형을 새로 짜도록 하고
Seiran is not doing any better than us in this chaos.
세이란과 토게츠 모두 비슷한 상황이니
Do not hope for any reinforcement.
지원은 기대하지 않는게 좋다
We'll clear a path to New Himuka's future with our own hands.
우리의 힘으로 뉴히무카의 미래에 한판 승부를 걸어보자
Yes!
예
Thank you for taking over the command while I was away.
지금까지 나 대신 버텨줘서
You have my gratitude.
정말 고마워
Yes!
예…
Shoot them! Shoot!
공격해, 얼른 공격하라고
Is everyone all right?
괜찮아?
The area of the eastern shelters has been cleared.
동쪽 지역 피난처 부근 처리 완료요
We made it in time.
우리 쪽도 완료입니다
Understood.
알았어
After you get everything under control, move on to the next shelter.
안정을 되찾을 때까지 기다렸다가 다른 피난처로 간다
This is...
여기는…
This is a hospital in Suoh.
스오의 병원이네
Did I...
내가 또…
How is everyone?
다들 괜찮아?
Yuito, you're finally awake.
유이토, 깼구나
That's great.
잘됐다
I remember hearing the Other alarm on the street of Suoh.
스오 거리에서… 괴이 경보음이 울렸던 것 같은데
The number of Others on the street has been reduced.
거리에 있던 괴이들은 줄었어
The incidence rate has gone down significantly as well.
출현률도 많이 내려갔고
But we can't let the civilians leave their shelters just yet.
하지만 피난처에 있는 사람들이 나올만한 정도는 아니야
I see.
그렇구나
The defense system hasn't been restored.
방어 시스템이 복구되지 않아서
We can't be sure if the Others will attack the streets again.
괴이가 언제 또 거리에 침입할지 몰라
We are awaiting orders from the headquarters.
지금 본부에서 대기 중이야
Meanwhile, we are preparing for the next battle.
언제든 또 싸워야 하니까
In that case, we need to head to the crypt now.
그럼 얼른 스메라기 릉으로 가야겠어
Yuito, are you all right?
유이토, 너 괜찮아?
Don't worry about me.
내 걱정은 마
I feel much better after the long sleep.
한잠 잤더니 개운해
We need to find Yakumo...
우리 얼른 야쿠모…
No, we need to find Karen
아니, 카렌을 찾아서
and undo the dimensional entanglement.
얽힌 차원부터 풀어야 해
We must settle this once and for all before it's too late.
더 이상 돌이킬 수 없기 전에 해결해야 해
Understood.
알았어
But you just woke up,
하지만 너 이제 막 깼잖아
we'll see how it goes for now.
일단 지켜보는게 좋겠어
Yes, I understand.
그래, 알았어
The Sumeragi crypt...
스메라기 릉이라…
Is Yuito really going to be OK?
유이토가… 진짜 괜찮은걸까
You heard what he said. We can only take his words for it.
본인이 괜찮다는데 믿을 수밖에
Indeed.
그러게
We should be worried about ourselves.
우리 자신부터 걱정해야 될 판이야
If my brother is inside the Sumeragi crypt,
형이 스메라기 릉에 있다면
I hope to persuade him.
설득할 수 있길 바래야지
But if that doesn't work...
설득이 안된다면…
A fight might be inevitable.
아마도 싸워야겠지
Agreed. We must be ready for the worst.
맞아, 각오부터 단단히 해야 돼
I know the world is full of dirty secrets and nonsense,
이 세상이 얼마나 추한지 알지만
but no matter how twisted it's become, ending it is not the right solution.
아무리 비뚤어진 세상이라고 해도 끝내는 건 말이 안돼
No matter what happens from now on, I won't abandon it.
앞으로 어떤 일이 있어도 난 절대 세상을 포기하지 않을 거야
What's so funny?
다들 왜 웃어
I see.
참
What?
뭔데?
It's the information about a dumpling shop.
계속 가고 싶었던
I've wanted to try it for quite some time.
군만두집이 있는데
Dumpling?
군만두?
But it seems like a place for youngsters.
젊은이들만 가는 곳인 것 같아
I'll have trouble fitting in.
난 들어가기 어렵겠지
In that case, I'll go with you.
그렇구나, 그럼 같이 가
I'm not exactly young anymore.
나도 썩 젊은 건 아니지만
You can count me in too.
그럼 나도 갈래
Me too! Count me in as well!
나도 나도 나도
I'm serious over here! Are you kidding me?
난 진지하다고, 갑자기 뭔 농담을 해?
The world will be safe with you around.
네가 있으니까 이 세상은 분명 아무 문제 없을 거야
Therefore, we should start making plans for our future.
그러니까 미래부터 계획해야 하지 않겠어?
I don't mind having dumplings.
나… 나도 군만두가 싫지는 않아
What's bothering you?
무슨 생각해?
Tsugumi...
츠구미
It's nothing.
별거 아니야…
Tsugumi, are you joining them?
츠구미… 너도 갈거야?
There are countless lives here,
여기에 중요한 생명들이 너무 많아
I don't want them to perish.
그 생명들이 사라지는 건 원치 않아
I'm sure you wouldn't want that either, Kagero.
카게로도 그렇게 생각해?
You are right about that.
그렇지 뭐…
But can you reconsider?
하지만 넌 다시 생각해보면 안될까?
If you insist on fighting Karen,
카렌과 싸우게 된다면
I might not be able to keep you safe.
츠구미 너를 지켜줄 수 있을지 모르겠어
I want you to survive.
난 네가 살았으면 좋겠거든
I'm not relying on you to protect me, Kagero.
네가 지켜줘야만 살 수 있는 건 싫어
I never want that.
나중에도 그렇고
You have a point.
그렇긴 하네
How could I possibly be so full of myself?
내가 자신을 너무 과대평가했어
Don't worry.
걱정 마
I believe everyone and I will still be able to crack some jokes with you.
나를 포함한 모두가 앞으로도 너와 웃고 떠들 수 있을 거라 믿어
Kagero, you should believe that too.
카게로도 그렇지
That's too harsh, Tsugumi.
너무해, 츠구미
I've always been very serious.
난 늘 진지했다고
You're joking again.
또 장난이네
No, I'm totally serious.
아니… 진짜라니까
Sister, you never change.
누나는 진짜 여전해
What?
뭐가
There are many things I'd like to comment on,
하고 싶은 말이 많지만 참을게
but can you at least don't eat in my room while lying on the couch?
그래도 내 방에 누워서 과자 좀 먹지 마
Don't mind me, I won't bother you.
난 신경쓰지 마
I have work tomorrow morning. It's almost bedtime for me.
내일 일찍 일어나야 해서 잘 건데
Go to bed if you want to.
그럼 가서 자
Sister, please leave.
누나, 나가줘
Come on.
에잇
You don't have to be so cold.
차가운 녀석
I don't remember raising you to be so stern.
누나가 널 이렇게 키웠었나
I don't remember you ever raising me.
누나가 날 키운거 아닌데
You're no fun.
재미 없긴
Sister, tomorrow...
누나, 내일…
We'll leave the streets to you.
거리는 너희한테 맡길게
Leave the monsters to us.
그 녀석들은 우리한테 맡겨
I'm sorry you have that troublesome friend.
귀찮은 친구를 둔 네가 고생이다
Yuito, are you...
유이토, 너 설마…
Kasane...
카사네
You're lucky I came to visit you.
내가 보러 오지 않으면 어쩔뻔했어
You're still too weak to move.
역시 아직은 움직이면 안돼
I'll be fine.
나 괜찮아
But your brain power...
하지만 네 초뇌능력이…
Listen to me!
내 말부터 들어줘
Nagi, Naomi, Captain Seto,
나기, 나오미, 세토 대장
I will never forget how they lost their lives.
그 사람들의 죽음을 평생 잊지 못할 것 같아
No matter how long it takes, I will never overcome it.
시간이 아무리 흘러도 마찬가지야…
This world is built upon sacrifices and tragedies.
지금 이 세상은 희생과 비애를 짓밟고 만들어진 거야
We are using brain power to heal the world,
초뇌능력으로 세상을 복구하면
but we pursue stronger power while we're at it.
또 더 강한 초뇌능력을 추구하겠지
Many have fallen into the abyss of madness.
이로 인해 더 많은 사람들이 미쳐갈 거야
We must put an end to all of this.
반드시 이 모든걸 끝내야 해
This world can't rely solely on brain power to survive.
초뇌능력만을 위해 존재하는 세상은 있을 수 없어
People who control brain power
초뇌능력을 사용하는 사람들이
will unknowingly become controlled by their own power.
자기도 모르는 사이에 초뇌능력의 제어를 받게 되니까
This is why I hope
난 이 세상이
we can live in a world where no one needs to rely on power to live.
뇌능력 없이도 살아갈 수 있도록 변했으면 좋겠어
That is why we must destroy the Kunad Gate.
때문에 반드시 쿠나도 게이트를 없애야 해
You sound very reliable.
듬직하네
At first, I thought you were just another unreliable brat.
솔직히 처음에는 네가 믿을만한 인물이 아니라고 생각했어
I could tell as much.
그럴 줄 알았어
But you're different now.
하지만 지금의 유이토는 달라
I believe you can change the world for the better.
난 네가 분명 이 세상을 바꿀 수 있을 거라 믿어
Thank you, Kasane.
고마워, 카사네
Don't mention it. I'll finally be able to go outside.
고맙긴, 그럼 나도 밖으로 나갈 수 있을 테니까
Outside?
밖이라면…
Yuito, Kasane, can you read me?
유이토, 카사네, 들려?
Loud and clear.
응
It's time to gather up.
집합하자
We'll move out in 15 minutes.
15분 뒤에 출발이야
Yes.
그래
I'll be right there.
지금 바로 갈게
Let's go
우리…
together.
함께 가자
Yes.
그래
Stay cautious.
조심해
Not even I can find any data
스메라기 릉 내부 자료는
about the Sumeragi crypt.
나도 못찾아
So it's a totally unknown realm in there.
여기가 미지의 영역이라는 뜻이겠네
This is...
이건…
What is this place?
이건 무슨 공간이야
Is this the OSF headquarters?
여기… 토벌군 본부야?
How did we suddenly get here?
어떻게 갑자기 여길 온거지?
We could have fallen into some kind of teleportation trap.
혹시 전송 뇌능력의 함정에 빠진건가?
All right, calm down.
자 자, 일단 침착하게
Look at the surrounding.
주위부터 둘러보자고
This place is without a doubt very creepy.
분명 이상한 곳이긴 해
I think it might have something to do with my brother's power.
아마 형의 초뇌능력과 연관되어 있을 것 같아
Other alert.
괴이 경보 발령
A large number of Others are raining down.
대량의 괴이가 출현했으니
Enter retaliation formation.
요격 모드에 들어간다
The Other incidence rate has increased.
괴이 출현 확률이 또 올라갔어
Brother!
형
Karen!
카렌
Luka, wait!
루카, 잠깐만
That might just be an illusion of Karen!
저 카렌이 실체가 아닐 수도 있어
But we still have to go.
그래도 가야 해
My sister was here before...
여긴 언니가 있었던…
Sister...
언니…
Kasane, watch out!
카사네, 물러 서
We are sitting ducks in here.
함정이야
Let's get out of here!
얼른 벗어나야 해
Kasane!
카사네
Roger!
알았어
I guess it won't be easy to get out of here.
도망가기 쉽지 않을 거야
Gemma, above you!
겜마, 위를 봐
This is...
여기는…
Nagi...
나기…
This is... back then...
이건 그때잖아…
What is going on now?
어떻게 된거지?
We are experiencing my brother's pain.
우리가… 형의 아픔을 느끼는 거야…
Now, we can all be together.
다들 늘 함께할 수 있을 거야
My chest...
가슴이…
No, the emotions will consume us.
안돼, 슬픈 감정에 휘말리고 있어…
Now, we can all be together.
늘 함께할 수 있을 거야
Together...
함께
Did I fail again?
내가 또… 실패한 건가…
Thank you, Kasane.
고마워, 카사네
Sister!
언니…
Please, live on for me too.
내 몫까지 함께 살아줘
What was that just now?
방금 그건…
Is everyone all right?
다들 괜찮아?
We can't stay here any longer.
더 이상 여기에 있으면 안돼
Let's leave.
얼른 가자
What is...
저건…
Not now.
아직 안돼
I can't lose my consciousness just yet.
아직 의식을 잃으면 안돼
Yakumo...
야쿠모…
Sumeragi...
스메라기
♫I'm troubled by my own yearning♫
추구하는 동경에 사로잡혀
♫Unveil the blocked sun ray♫
아른거리며 앞을 막는 햇볕을 제껴
♫There's a stranger in me♫
There's a stranger in me
♫That I've never seen♫
여태 본 적이 없어
♫I can not soar in the sky without fear♫
공포는 묻어두고 하늘 높이 날 수 있을까
♫I'm spreading my wings♫
I'm spreading my wings
♫Dancing gracefully like a bird♫
예쁘게 춤추는 새들과
♫And gazing towards the scarlet sky♫
빨갛게 물든 하늘을 쳐다봐
♫I chased after the gust♫
강한 바람을 따라가
♫The scenery spreads into the ever-changing world♫
변해가는 세계에 경치가 퍼지고 있어
♫Inside the intertwined brilliance♫
뒤얽힌 빛 속에서
♫I'm still searching for tomorrow's direction♫
계속해 내일 걸어갈 길을 찾아
♫Tomorrow's in your hands♫
Tomorrow's in your hands
♫Don't tell me now you're afraid♫
Don't tell me now you're afraid
♫There's no time to waste♫
There's no time to waste
♫Go forward♫
나아가
♫Have no fear for anything♫
더 이상 아무것도 두려워하지 마
♫Now, let's go♫
함께 가
♫Into a brand new day♫
Into a brand new day
THE YEARNING IN SLUMBER
(그리움이 잠들다)